So we're going to start with, how to slip or dodge a punch.
As you know for fighting, sparring, any situation defending yourself.
There maybe that the person is hitting you back.
So how do you get away from that.
Well, you've got to learn how to slip.
So again, you have to start with the staggered stance.
So you have balance.
Make sure you have the hip width apart, same position that you set up for a punch.
Hands are always up.
The most common mistake people make, slipping, is they look at the floor as they go down.
O.k.
If you look at the floor and you come up, you don't know what's waiting for you, as you come up.
So anytime, somebody's throwing a punch at you.
And you're trying to get away from it.
You want to still keep your eyes on your opponent as you're going underneath that punch.
O.k., so pretend just straight punch is coming at you. You want to go underneath it. At the same time protect your face and your rib cage.
You just went from right to left.
And we just went underneath that punch, making half a circle.
So one more time, step over and under.
And come up on the other side.
O.k.
Make sure you don't look at the floor, this whole time.
And that your hands stay up.
Keep your eyes on your opponent the whole time you're moving underneath that arm, or that punch, to make sure you know, what's coming at you.
The second you get up from that slip.
Now you can do two of them.
You can slip underneath.
If another punch is coming.
Or moving back.
O.k., so that's two slips.
One and two.
Get ready to throw a punch.
Right after you come out of that slip.
Next, we're going to work on simple combinations starting with jab cross.